prettymummasays.com 2019-03-31

# Privacy Policy - Pretty Mumma Says - http://www.prettymummasays.com

### I am Surbhi Mahobia, owner and proprietor of Pretty Mumma Says who runs and operates the [http://www.prettymummasays.com](http://www.prettymummasays.com/) website.

This page is made to inform you of my website policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data (name, email address and website URL, if any) when you visit my website and leave your personal data while initiating any interaction with me.

I use your personal data to provide and improve your experience on my website. By filling your personal data, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, accessible from [http://www.prettymummasays.com](http://www.prettymummasays.com/)

Through my website, several different types of information is gathered for various purposes to provide and improve my website experience and the quality of content for you.

## Types of Data Collected

### Personal Data

While visiting my website, I may ask you to provide certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you (“Personal Data”). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:

  * Email address
  * First name and last name
  * Cookies and Usage Data

### Usage Data

Through my website, I may also collect information about how my website is accessed and used (“Usage Data”). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of my website that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

### Tracking & Cookies Data

Cookies and similar tracking technologies may be used to track the activity on my website and hold certain information.

Cookies are files with small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Tracking technologies also used are beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze my website.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use or view some portions of my website.

Examples of Cookies:

  * **Session Cookies.** Session Cookies to operate our Service.
  * **Preference Cookies.** Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings.
  * **Security Cookies.** Security Cookies for security purposes.

### Use of Data

Pretty Mumma Says uses the collected data for various purposes:

  * To provide and maintain the website
  * To notify you about changes to my website
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of my website when you choose to do so
  * To provide analysis or valuable information to improve the website
  * To monitor the usage of the website
  * To detect, prevent and address technical issues

### Transfer Of Data

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

If you are located outside India and choose to provide information through the website, please note that I transfer the data, including Personal Data, to India and process it there.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

Pretty Mumma Says will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

## Disclosure Of Data

### Legal Requirements

Pretty Mumma Says may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

  * To comply with a legal obligation
  * To protect and defend the rights or property of Pretty Mumma Says
  * To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the website
  * To protect the personal safety of users of the website or the public
  * To protect against legal liability

### Security Of Data

The security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

### Service Providers

I may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate my website (“Service Providers”), to provide the website on my behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist me in analyzing how my website is used.

These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on my behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

The website may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of my wesbite.

  * **Google Analytics**

Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of my website. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

You can opt-out of having made your activity on the website available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity.

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: <https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en>

The content on this website is original and bears no resemblance to any other content on the internet. If you wish you use my articles or images on your website, please seek an approval be sending a request on [prettymummasays@gmail.com](mailto:prettymummasays@gmail.com).

All the content and images on this website is protected by [Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-NoDerivatives 4.0 International License](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/4.0/)

None of the articles on this website should be treated as a medical advice. This is a parenting and lifestyle blog where I share my personal experiences.

The images used on this website are taken from free resource websites, my personal repository and the credits are given if the images are taken from any other source.

Any sort of plagiarism will be reported and legal action will be taken against the doer.

My website may contain links to other sites that are not operated by me. If you click on a third-party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site. I strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

I don’t have and hold no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

I may update my Privacy Policy from time to time. I will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

### If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact me by sending an email to [prettymummasays@gmail.com](mailto:prettymummasays@gmail.com)
